Joseph S. Ortega

720-202-9772 | MyAgentOrtega@Gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/MyAgentOrtega https://github.com/MyAgentOrtega

EDUCATION

THE UNIVERSITY OF DENVER | UNIVERSITY COLLEGE, DENVER, CO

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp - Currently enrolled

Spring 2023

Certificate- Full Stack Web development

THE UNIVERSITY OF DENVER | DANIELS COLLEGE OF BUSINESS, DENVER, CO

FRANKLIN L. BURNS SCHOOL OF REAL ESTATE AND CONSTRUCTION MANAGEMENT - GPA 3.50

Fall 2019

Bachelor of Science Business Administration- Real Estate Development and Construction Management

SUMMARY:

Motivated and skilled Full Stack Web Developer with a background in real estate development and construction management. Strong project management and communication skills, with experience in underground utility placement, data analysis, and time-sensitive documentation distribution.

RELEVANT SKILLS/ACCOLADES

- Autodesk suite software experienced
- J.D. Edwards EnterpriseOne (E1) software
- Bluebeam software
- CMiC Project Management SoftwareMicrosoft.
- Office Specialist: Excel, PowerPoint, and Word
- Bilingual (Fluent: English and Spanish)
- Non-profit board member- The Perfect Peace Project (Poverty Alleviation)

- Google: Python Crash Course & Technical Support Fundamentals certificates
- Full stack web development: HTML5, CSS3,
 JavaScript, ¡Query, Express.js, React.js, Node.js,
 progressive web apps, agile methodology,
 computer science, database theory, MongoDB,
 MySQL, Git
- Published Article: Colorado Real Estate Journal

EXPERIENCE

LOKAL HOMES 08/2021 - 03/2022

Denver, CO

Land Development Specialist/Construction Management

- Ensured accurate underground utility placement per site plan (water, sewer, communication, and electric)
- Coordinated efforts with city/county inspectors, and vertical construction teams to maintain scheduled construction efforts
- Managed asphalt, concrete, soil engineers, field crew schedules for horizontal real estate developments
- Completed city (HOA) punch list items for construction bond releases

RICHMOND AMERICAN HOMES (MDC HOLDINGS)

11/2020 - 03/2021

Denver, CO

Options Specialist/Data Analyst

- Maintained and updated data on J.D. Edwards EnterpriseOne (E1) software for various national markets.
- Communicated goals and objectives with national sales and home gallery teams through detailed communication.
- Accurately updated new home build options and maintained profitable margins through data analysis and reports.
- Extensive use of E1 software to create a vast array of templates and customized community product builds for field team use.
- Updated and Maintained PlayerLync software for sales, marketing, and field use.

SAUNDERS CONSTRUCTION INC.

07/2019 - 12/2019

Denver, CO

Project Engineer Intern/Construction Management

- Effectively distribute time-sensitive documentation to subcontractors, team, and owner representatives
- Create and effectively communicate RFI's, bulletins, field drawings, office drawings, and as-builts
- Conducted extensive research to provide successful submittal processes which led to 95% total submittal completion
- Led close-out process for owner record (Operation, Maintenance, Warranty, Owner Stock, Owner Training, etc.)
- Managed implementation of a 360 degree image program for time lapse, liability and record keeping functions